var questions = [{
  question: 'Information Systems Importance',
  color: 'yellow',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) List three reasons why information systems are important in modern society.',
    answer: 'Information systems are the most complex artifacts yet built and are essential to modern society in a number of ways, such as, Health and well-being; Security; Commerce; Entertainment; Transport; Productivity'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Describe the two most important causes of information systems failure in your opinion, and give two examples of high profile IT project failures, indicating what went wrong.',
    answer: 'Failure on information systems happen quite often, in fact, it is debatable that information systems projects fails more often then succeeds, two of the most important reasons for informations systems failure are poor communication and engaging in projects that are over ambitious. Two good examples of high profile IT project failures are the National Programme for Information Technology (NPfIT) held by the NHS and the Transfer and Automated Registration of Uncertificated Stock (TAURUS), held by the London Stock Exchange, costing billions and millions respectively to their stakeholders.'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Who was Charles Babbage, and what was the Difference Engine?',
    answer: 'Charles Babbage was an English mathematician, best remembered for originating the concept of a programmable computer. A difference engine is an automatic mechanical calculator designed to tabulate polynomial functions.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Freedom of Information',
  color: 'blue',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is the purpose of the Freedom of Information (FoI) Act 2000 and who does it apply to?',
    answer: 'Freedom of Information legislation is designed to make public organisations more open and accountable. It gives the right to access to information held by most public authorities and applies to: central and local government departments; the NHS; education authorities; military services, and so on. It excludes the Intelligence services and parts of the BBC.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) What are the grounds for complaint under the FoI Act?',
    answer: 'The grounds for complaint under the FoI Act are: Not responded the request in a timely manner; Does not give proper advice and help; Does not give information in the form requested; Does not explain properly reasons for refusing request.'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Where can one typically find information about an organisation’s commitment to the FoI Act? What are Birkbeck’s obligations under the FoI Act?',
    answer: 'Every public authority must make some information available as a matter of routine through a publication scheme. For Birkbeck, a publication scheme is both a public commitment to make certain information available and a guide to how that information can be obtained. It contains information about how to file Freedom of Information requests and the associated process. It also contains information about how to make a complaint.'
  },
  {
    question: 'd) Doc Sportello is a private individual who wants to know more about the Gravity Rainbow project, a high value UK trade deal to sell rockets to the Ruritanians. This has been widely reported in the press, although the sale is still being debated in Parliament. Can the FoI Act help Doc?',
    answer: 'Doc Sportello could apply for a Freedom of Information request but would probably be refused due to affecting public relations a harm based exemption as well as a absolute exemption for its disclosure may infringe parliamentary privilege and conduct of public affairs.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'You work for a software company that is developing bespoke software for Teledyne Corporation, a robotics firm. The contract for this work is in two phases: the first, a time and materials (T&M) contract to agree project scope and a work plan; and the second phase a fixed price contract for the actual development work.',
  color: 'green',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Explain the difference between a T&M and Fixed Price contract.',
    answer: 'Time and materials: Payment is based on number of hours/days worked and expenses incurred. It is more typical for consultancy than for software development. Risks are shared between client and supplier. Fixed price contract: A fixed amount is agreed for the complete work - quite common in software development. The supplier usually charges a fixed price premium because he takes most of the risk.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Why it is of benefit both to you AND to Teledyne to contract in this way?',
    answer: 'The advantage to you of contracting in this way is because at the outset, you can validate the scope of the project before committing to a fixed price. This will allow you to validate requirements and develop more accurate cost estimates and schedules. This reduces the risk to you in entering a fixed price development phase (where you will bear the full risk). You agree a T&M contract for the initial work because you are unfamiliar with the clients requirements and working environment, so are unsure of how long you will need to spend on the scoping, and a T&M contract will ensure you get paid for all the time you spend, so is less risky. For the client, contracting with you for a small T&M scoping project will allow him to identify any ambiguity or uncertainty around requirements, and therefore will result in a more accurate specification and plan. Agreeing a fixed price for the development phase provides certainty around cost and scope of the deliverable.'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) During the project you develop new unique code for Teledyne. Describe three ways in which such Intellectual Property is protected and identify which is most appropriate in this case.',
    answer: 'The three ways in which creative work can be protected by law are Patents which protect inventions, formulae, algorithms, and so on; Trademarks which protect manufacturers and suppliers - product names, logos and so on; and Copyright which covers the right to copy a piece of work. Since Teledyne is a robotics company, depending on jurisdiction, the software could be patented as part of a patentable physical product. Although patents are a powerful protective framework, they are expensive and take time to be processed, making it harder for smaller companies to achieve then for big companies. If the software does not represent a physical product, the software may not be patentable, in which case, smaller novel pieces of the software could be patented individually, such as formulae and algorithms. In the other hand, although less powerful then patents, the software will be automatically protected by copyright from the moment it came to existence. Patents last for 20 years in contrast with copyright which lasts 70. In this case the most appropriate form of protection is copyright, which generally goes to the customer unless specified in the contract.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Data Protection',
  color: 'red',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Alice wants to build a client mailing list for her new online book store and wonders if Data Protection laws are relevant to her business. Can you provide four Data Protection principles that apply to her case?',
    answer: 'Personal data shall be processed fairly and lawfully and in particular shall not be processed unless (a) data subject has given their consent and (b) for sensitive data has given their explicit consent, meaning that it has to be clearly consent, failing to tick an opt-out box is not sufficient; Personal data shall be processed in accordance with the rights of the data subjects, meaning that Data controllers must tell the Information Commissioner what data they are collecting and the purpose for which it is being collected; Personal data shall be adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purpose or purposes for which they are processed, meaning that Data that is not needed can’t be collected, for example shops collecting a customer’s address when not delivering goods; Personal data shall be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date, this is can be hard to do, for example, universities find it hard to keep student addresses up to date'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Alice wants to know if there are other regulations that apply to her new online business, particularly around contracting. What is your advice?',
    answer: 'EU Electronic Commerce Directive, 2002 applies to contracts concluded by electronic means over distance whereby the buyer is a consumer.; Consumer Protection (Distance Selling) Regulations 2000 – applies to goods and services sold over the radio, internet, digital television, mail order, phone, fax; Electronic Signature Directive - establishes the legal framework at European level for electronic signatures and certification services; Electronic Money Institutions Directive – new legislation in 2011 will (amongst other things) allow banks and building societies to issue electronic money; VAT on products delivered electronically - applicable to radio and television broadcasting services and certain electronically supplied services'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Software Engineering Profession',
  color: 'purple',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Describe clearly the pros and cons for regulation of the software engineering profession.',
    answer: 'Pros: Many IT systems are mission critical, so it would help prevent disaster; It would introduce best practice  and improve IT quality; It would provide a basis for standard training and accreditation; It would provide assurance to customers; It would help the profession mature; It’s necessary to have professional status to attract the best talent; It would provide a central register of qualified SEs; Cons: Most software is not mission-critical; It would drive SE underground or offshore – with potential loss of quality; It’s hard to agree a standard career path or qualifications for a computer; It would reduce number of SEs – so more project delays and increased cost; It would stifle innovation; The SE industry is doing well enough without regulation!; It would be hard to enforce – lots of software engineers have not had formal training;'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) State exactly what reserving ‘title’ and ‘function’ of a profession means, providing an example of a profession for which both title and function are reserved.',
    answer: 'A profession may reserve the title, meaning that one cannot call oneself that title unless registered with the appropriate professional entity, The same applies for a job function with the exception that instead of carrying the title, one cannot carry out the duties of the given job without being registered. A combination of both title and function may also be reserved, for example, in the UK, one must be registered with the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons (RCVS) to call oneself a vet, and to carry out surgical procedures on animals'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) In 2010, Google was sued by Viacom for infringement of copyright by its subsidiary YouTube. Describe the legal argument at the base of the litigation and the outcome.',
    answer: 'YouTube won the case based on the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), which essentially means that ISPs, aggregators and social networking services can`t be held responsible for copyright infringement as long as they take reasonable steps to address the issue once it\'s flagged-up by the copyright holder. One of the reasons for choosing this is because they had implemented hashing technology to block videos that have already been removed. Youtube bought a licence to Finger printing technology that scans all videos before they are uploaded and this referenced against a library for participating copyright owners. They can monitor/ track uploaded videos and monetize the content by allowing advertising to run along side it'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Data Protection',
  color: 'red',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is the purpose of data protection legislation? Describe four of the principles that underpin data protection legislation in the UK.',
    answer: 'Legislation is needed to ensure protection of data and privacy even though information may be hard to find or to track. Four of it`s priciples are: Personal data shall be processed fairly and lawfully and in particular shall not be processed unless (a) data subject has given their consent and (b) for sensitive data has given their explicit consent, meaning that it has to be clearly consent, failing to tick an opt-out box is not sufficient; Personal data shall be processed in accordance with the rights of the data subjects, meaning that Data controllers must tell the Information Commissioner what data they are collecting and the purpose for which it is being collected; Personal data shall be adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purpose or purposes for which they are processed, meaning that Data that is not needed can’t be collected, for example shops collecting a customer’s address when not delivering goods; Personal data shall be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date, this is can be hard to do, for example, universities find it hard to keep student addresses up to date.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) What does the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulation 2003 cover? What do the amended regulations say about website cookies?',
    answer: 'Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulations 2003: protects a citizen’s right to “privacy”. It covers rules on related areas including use of cookies, telephone directories, traffic, location data and security breaches. The amend on the regulation imposes more stringent obligations upon website developers regarding cookies (awareness, purpose, consent)'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) What is the purpose of Freedom of information regulation in the UK and who does it apply to? What are the Environmental Information Regulations for?',
    answer: 'Freedom of Information legislation is designed to make public organisations more open and accountable. It gives the right to access to information held by most public authorities and applies to: central and local government departments; the NHS; education authorities; military services, and so on. It excludes the Intelligence services and parts of the BBC. Environmental Regulations are a statutory right of access to environmental information held by UK public authorities. Such as information about air, water, soil, land, flora and fauna, energy, noise, waste and emissions. Also includes information about decisions, policies and activities that affect the environment.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Information Systems Importance',
  color: 'yellow',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) The National Programme for IT comprised a series of IS projects designed to provide modern IS for the NHS in the UK. The programme was terminated in 2011, and was widely regarded as an example of a failed IS programme. Write a short essay (2 pages) describing why this programme is of interest to IS professionals. You should refer to the importance of IS systems in society, reasons for failure and implications on IS professionalism.',
    answer: 'I don\'t know yet'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Intellectual Property',
  color: 'orange',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Your friend Steve Gates has developed new software to control how printers optimise use of ink. He doesn’t know how to protect his innovation and comes to you for advice. What can you tell him about the pros and cons of copyrighting and patenting software?',
    answer: 'Patents protect inventions, formulae, algorithms, and so on and Copyright covers the right to copy a piece of work. Since Steve Gate\`s is developing software to control printers, a physical product, depending on jurisdiction, the software could be patented as part of a patentable physical product. Although patents are a powerful protective framework, they are expensive and take time to be processed, making it harder for smaller companies to achieve then for big companies. If the software does not represent a physical product, the software may not be patentable, in which case, smaller novel pieces of the software could be patented individually, such as formulae and algorithms. In the other hand, although less powerful then patents, the software will be automatically protected by copyright from the moment it came to existence. Patents last for 20 years in contrast with copyright which lasts 70.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Steve’s day job is with Applesoft, and he mentions that he actually developed his new software as a bespoke solution for an Applesoft client, but that the client has told him it has no interest in exploiting this invention. How does this colour your advice for Steve?',
    answer: 'Copyright generally goes to the author, however, since this piece of software was developed for a client, unless stated in the contract, the client has the right to retain the copyright for the software. An amendment to the contract between the client and Applesoft would be appropriate in this situation, since the client does not have interest in retain the rights to the intellectual property, the client would probably agree with transferring the rights back to the developer.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Intellectual Property',
  color: 'orange',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is Intellectual Property (IP) (provide some examples)? What are the three ways in which IP can be protected in the law?',
    answer: 'Intellectual Property is the name given to legal rights which protect creative works, inventions and commercial goodwill. It protects creative works such as Ideas; Books; Music; Algorithms. The three ways in which intellectual property can be protected by law are Patents which protect inventions, formulae, algorithms, and so on; Trademarks which protect manufacturers and suppliers - product names, logos and so on; and Copyright which covers the right to copy a piece of work. One does not need to apply to be protected by copyright, it comes to existence as the new creative work comes to existence. Although not legally as powerful as patents, copyright lasts for 70 years. Patents are a powerful way to protect intellectual property, one must apply for patent, they are expensive and take time to be processed, which in turn generally benefits big companies over small companies. Patents generally work in a first come first served basis and last for 20 years.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) What is Internet governance and what types of issues is it concerned with? Which bodies oversee Internet governance?',
    answer: 'Internet governance is the development and application by Governments, the private  sector & civil society, in their respective roles, of shared principles, norms, rules, decision-making procedures, & programmes that shape the evolution & use of the Internet. It is concerned with: Infrastructure (Domain Name System, IP addresses); Security, safety and privacy (e.g. abuse, spam, cyber crime); Intellectual property and international trade (including copyrights); Development Issues (particularly developing countries). The bodies which oversee Internet governance are: Internet Governance Forum (IGF); United Nations Working Group on Internet Governance (WGIG); Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICAAN); Internet Watch Foundation (IWF)'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Write a short essay concerning the rules and practices that concern the use of e-mail and Internet by employees, describing such aspects as the rights and obligations of employers, when an employee’s account can be monitored, and other guidelines that are usually followed.',
    answer: 'I don\'t know yet'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Software Engineering Profession',
  color: 'purple',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Some people believe that the IS profession should be regulated, and the title of software engineer reserved. Describe exactly what reserving title and function mean, and set out your views on the advantages and disadvantages of this proposal.',
    answer: 'A profession may reserve the title, meaning that one cannot call oneself that title unless registered with the appropriate professional entity, The same applies for a job function with the exception that instead of carrying the title, one cannot carry out the duties of the given job without being registered. A combination of both title and function may also be reserved, for example, in the UK, one must be registered with the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons (RCVS) to call oneself a vet, and to carry out surgical procedures on animals. Pros: Many IT systems are mission critical, so it would help prevent disaster; It would introduce best practice  and improve IT quality; It would provide a basis for standard training and accreditation; It would provide assurance to customers; It would help the profession mature; It’s necessary to have professional status to attract the best talent; It would provide a central register of qualified SEs; Cons: Most software is not mission-critical; It would drive SE underground or offshore – with potential loss of quality; It’s hard to agree a standard career path or qualifications for a computer; It would reduce number of SEs – so more project delays and increased cost; It would stifle innovation; The SE industry is doing well enough without regulation!; It would be hard to enforce – lots of software engineers have not had formal training;'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Your friend has put together an album of family photos that she wants to put on Facebook. She’s used a U2 song as a background music track for the album slide show. What advice could you give her about this? What is YouTube’s position on copyright infringement?',
    answer: 'YouTube won the case based on the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), which essentially means that ISPs, aggregators and social networking services can`t be held responsible for copyright infringement as long as they take reasonable steps to address the issue once it\'s flagged-up by the copyright holder. One of the reasons for choosing this is because they had implemented hashing technology to block videos that have already been removed. Youtube bought a licence to Finger printing technology that scans all videos before they are uploaded and this referenced against a library for participating copyright owners. They can monitor/ track uploaded videos and monetize the content by allowing advertising to run along side it'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Your software company is selected to develop a bespoke software programme for a small insurance firm. You agree with your client to contract for this work in two phases: the first, a time and materials (T&M) contract for a short scoping exercise at the beginning of the project to agree a work plan; and the second phase a fixed price contract for the actual development work.',
  color: 'green',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Explain the difference between a T&M and Fixed Price contract;',
    answer: 'Time and materials: Payment is based on number of hours/days worked and expenses incurred.  It is more typical for consultancy than for software development.  Risks are shared between client and supplier. Fixed price contract: A fixed amount is agreed for the complete work - quite common in software development. The supplier usually charges a fixed price premium because he takes most of the risk.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Why it is of benefit to you AND to your client to contract in this way?',
    answer: 'The advantage to you of contracting in this way is because at the outset, you can validate the scope of the project before committing to a fixed price.  This will allow you to validate requirements and develop more accurate cost estimates and schedules.  This reduces the risk to you in entering a fixed price development phase (where you will bear the full risk). You agree a T&M contract for the initial work because you are unfamiliar with the clients requirements and working environment, so are unsure of how long you will need to spend on the scoping, and a T&M contract will ensure you get paid for all the time you spend, so is less risky.  For the client, contracting with you for a small T&M scoping project will allow him to identify any ambiguity or uncertainty around requirements, and therefore will result in a more accurate specification and plan. Agreeing a fixed price for the development phase provides certainty around cost and scope of the deliverable.'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) During the development phase, the client asks for a new function, not specified in the original requirement. How do you deal with this contractually?',
    answer: 'You invoke the change control procedure, which you have specified in the contract. This specifies how changes are managed, and how they are priced and scheduled.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Your local Council has decided to close the library in your neighbourhood and open a swimming pool in its place. Your neighbour is angered by this and wants to find out how the Council came to this decision. She believes she can use Freedom of Information Act to get disclosure and asks you for help about this legislation.',
  color: 'blue',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Describe the purpose of the UK Freedom of information Act, 2000; who it applies to; and what bodies it excludes',
    answer: 'Freedom of Information legislation is designed to make public organisations more open and accountable. It gives the right to access to information held by most public authorities and applies to: central and local government departments, including your neighbour’s Council; NHS; education authorities; military services, and so on. It excludes the Intelligence services and parts of the BBC.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Your neighbour asks about the publication scheme. Describe what this is and what type of information should be contained in the Council’s publication scheme.',
    answer: 'Every public authority must make some information available as a matter of routine through a publication scheme. A publication scheme is both a public commitment to make certain information available and a guide to how that information can be obtained. It contains information about how to file Freedom of Information requests and the associated process. It also contains information about how to make a complaint.'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Provide some guidance to your neighbour about what response she can expect from the Council and under what circumstances she can complain if she is unhappy with the information provided.',
    answer: 'Based on Environmental Information Regulations, your neighbour can expect information about decisions, policies and activities that affect the environment including water, air, fauna, flora, soil, land, energy, noise, waste, emissions. Your neighbour can complain if the Council does not: Respond in a timely manner to her Freedom of Information request; Give proper advice and help; Give information in the form requested; Explain properly reason for refusing request.'
  },
  {
    question: 'd) How might the Environmental Information Regulations, 2004 help your neighbour’s investigations with regard to the swimming pool?',
    answer: 'The Environmental Information Regulations provide a statutory right of access to environmental information held by UK public authorities, including the Council. Under this legislation, a citizen can ask a public body to provide information about decisions, policies and activities that affect the environment. Your neighbour could use this to ask the council for information about the environmental impact of building a swimming pool.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Computer Misuse',
  color: 'dark',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Your security software identifies that your computer has been accessed by someone with an IP address outside the EU. On examination, you determine that none of your files have been changed or erased in any way, and your computer is clear of malware. Explain what offences described in the Computer Misuse Act, 1990 might be of use to you in prosecuting the hacker. Point out also some of the ways in which the current legislation on computer misuse might be of limited value.',
    answer: 'The Act created three new offences: Unauthorised access to computer material; Unauthorised access with intent to commit or facilitate commission of further offences; Unauthorised modification of computer material; A person is guilty of an offence if he causes a computer to perform any function with intent to secure access to any program or data held in any computer [or to enable any such access to be secured]; the access he intends to secure [or to enable to be secured] is unauthorised; and he knows at the time when he causes the computer to perform the function that that is the case.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) What does Part 5 of the Police & Justice Bill, 2006 contain and what do these provisions do?',
    answer: 'Part 5 of this Act contains amendments to the Computer Misuse Act 1990; Increased maximum penalty for attempting to gain unauthorised access from 6 months to 12 months; Made impairing the operation of a computer an offence with a maximum penalty of 12 months; Made it an offence to make, adapt or supply tools for use in offences against the Computer Misuse Act'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'E-Commerce',
  color: 'pastel',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is e-commerce? Describe what is meant by ‘B2B’, B2C’ and ‘C2C’.',
    answer: 'E-Commerce is the practice of distance selling goods (whether electronic or physical) over an electronic media, such as the internet and telephone. B2B stands for business to business transactions, for example, an investment bank that negotiates with another investment bank. B2C stands for business to customer, for example, a business that sells clothes over an internet website; and C2C stands for customer to customer, eBay, for example.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) List some of the provisions in the Consumer Protection (Distance Selling) Regulations, 2000 that help protect consumers transacting business on the Internet.',
    answer: 'Information to provide before contract is made: Identity and address of supplier,  Description of goods and services, Price of goods and services including all taxes,  Delivery costs, arrangement for payment, delivery and performance, existence of a right of cancellation, costs of using the means of distance communication, period of which offer is valid, minimum duration of contract (permanent, recurrent), geographical address of supplier, information about after-sales services); To be made available “in writing or in another durable medium which is available and accessible to the consumer” (e.g. printable email)'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Describe the objectives of the European Charter of Rights of Citizens in the Knowledge Society, 2006.',
    answer: 'I don\'t know yet'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Intellectual Property',
  color: 'orange',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Define what is meant by Intellectual Property (IP) and provide some examples. What are three ways in which IP can be protected in the law?',
    answer: 'Intellectual Property is the name given to legal rights which protect creative works, inventions and commercial goodwill. It protects creative works such as Ideas; Books; Music; Algorithms. The three ways in which intellectual property can be protected by law are Patents which protect inventions, formulae, algorithms, and so on; Trademarks which protect manufacturers and suppliers - product names, logos and so on; and Copyright which covers the right to copy a piece of work. One does not need to apply to be protected by copyright, it comes to existence as the new creative work comes to existence. Although not legally as powerful as patents, copyright lasts for 70 years. Patents are a powerful way to protect intellectual property, one must apply for patent, they are costly and take time to be processed. Patents generally work in a first come first served basis and last for 20 years.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) You are an employee of Softco, a company that develops a bespoke funds transfer software application for a bank. Your role is to develop the code for the module that calculates commission; you do this by using a combination of custom and open-source code, and your work is acknowledged as an original and valuable contribution. In this situation, describe how ownership of IP is assigned. Do you have a claim to IP?',
    answer: 'Depends on the contract agreed between the developer and Softco, customer usually gets the copyright but there may be proprietary elements for which the developer retains copyright and can sell the customer a licence to use; The open-source elements copyright will be stated in their respective licences;'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) In 2010, Google was sued by Viacom for infringement of copyright by its subsidiary YouTube. Discuss the pros and cons of this case, indicating whether - in your opinion - the judgement was fair.',
    answer: 'YouTube won the case based on the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA), which essentially means that ISPs, aggregators and social networking services can`t be held responsible for copyright infringement as long as they take reasonable steps to address the issue once it\'s flagged-up by the copyright holder. One of the reasons for choosing this is because they had implemented hashing technology to block videos that have already been removed. Youtube bought a licence to Finger printing technology that scans all videos before they are uploaded and this referenced against a library for participating copyright owners. They can monitor/ track uploaded videos and monetize the content by allowing advertising to run along side it'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Challenges in Software Development',
  color: 'yellow',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Describe briefly the importance of information systems. Describe some of the causes of information systems failure.',
    answer: 'Information systems are essential to modern society in a number of ways, such as, Health and well-being; Security; Commerce; Entertainment; Transport; Productivity. Failure on information systems happen quite often, in fact, it is debatable that information systems projects fails more often then succeeds, two of the most important reasons for informations systems failure are poor communication and engaging in projects that are over ambitious. Two good examples of high profile IT project failures are the National Programme for Information Technology (NPfIT) held by the NHS and the Transfer and Automated Registration of Uncertificated Stock (TAURUS), held by the London Stock Exchange, costing billions and millions respectively to their stakeholders.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Describe the Child Support Agency CS2 project in the UK and suggest some of the causes of failure.',
    answer: 'I don\'t know yet'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Why do you think information systems are poorly understood by the public?',
    answer: 'Information systems are the most complex artifacts yet built, they are a comparatively recent discipline and are mostly very abstract. For example a rail control system is mostly `invisible`. Before PCs/Internet, most public use was limited (e.g. ATMs)'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'The IT Profession',
  color: 'purple',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What are the key characteristics and functions of a profession in the UK? List some of the professional bodies in computing in the USA and the UK.',
    answer: 'A profession exists to provide confidence around the quality of the service delivered, particularly in matters of life and death. Specifies training requirements for members; Controls entry to profession; Provides accreditation for related activities; Specifies and enforces a code of conduct for members; Acts as an advisor on related matters; Defines and publicises good practice and new developments. Some of the professional bodies in computing in the UK and USA are the IEEE, the IET and the BCS.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) Describe what is meant by a reserved title when used in the context of a particular profession, and provide an example. Describe what is meant by a reserved title and function, and provide an example.',
    answer: 'A profession may reserve the title, meaning that one cannot call oneself that title unless registered with the appropriate professional entity, for example, only those registered with the Architects Registration Board can call themselves architects. The same applies for a job function with the exception that instead of carrying the title, one cannot carry out the duties of the given job without being registered. A combination of both title and function may also be reserved, for example, in the UK, one must be registered with the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons (RCVS) to call oneself a vet, and to carry out surgical procedures on animals'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Describe some of the issues associated with reserving the software engineering title and function.',
    answer: 'Pros: Many IT systems are mission critical, so it would help prevent disaster; It would introduce best practice  and improve IT quality; It would provide a basis for standard training and accreditation; It would provide assurance to customers; It would help the profession mature; It’s necessary to have professional status to attract the best talent; It would provide a central register of qualified SEs; Cons: Most software is not mission-critical; It would drive SE underground or offshore – with potential loss of quality; It’s hard to agree a standard career path or qualifications for a computer; It would reduce number of SEs – so more project delays and increased cost; It would stifle innovation; The SE industry is doing well enough without regulation!; It would be hard to enforce – lots of software engineers have not had formal training;'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Freedom of Information',
  color: 'blue',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is the purpose of the Freedom of Information Act 2000? In the UK, who does it apply to? What bodies does it exclude?',
    answer: 'Freedom of Information legislation is designed to make public organisations more open and accountable. It gives the right to access to information held by most public authorities and applies to: central and local government departments; the NHS; education authorities; military services, and so on. It excludes the Intelligence services and parts of the BBC.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) List five of the `absolute exemptions` from the Act.',
    answer: 'Information that is accessible by other means; Information relating to or dealing with security matters; Information contained in court records; Where disclosure of the information would infringe parliamentary privilege; Information held by the House of Commons or the House of Lords, where disclosure would prejudice the effective conduct of public affairs ; Information which the applicant could obtain under the Data Protection Act; Information where release would breach the data protection principles; Information provided in confidence; When disclosing the information is prohibited by an enactment; incompatible with an EU obligation; or would commit a contempt of court'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) What is a publication scheme? What are the grounds under which a citizen can complain that their Freedom of Information request has not been answered?',
    answer: 'Every public authority must make some information available as a matter of routine through a publication scheme. a publication scheme is both a public commitment to make certain information available and a guide to how that information can be obtained. It contains information about how to file Freedom of Information requests and the associated process. It also contains information about how to make a complaint. The grounds for complaint under the FoI Act are: Not responded the request in a timely manner; Does not give proper advice and help; Does not give information in the form requested; Does not explain properly reasons for refusing request.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Data Protection',
  color: 'red',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) Describe four of the principles that underpin data protection legislation in the UK.',
    answer: 'Personal data shall be processed fairly and lawfully and in particular shall not be processed unless (a) data subject has given their consent and (b) for sensitive data has given their explicit consent, meaning that it has to be clearly consent, failing to tick an opt-out box is not sufficient; Personal data shall be processed in accordance with the rights of the data subjects, meaning that Data controllers must tell the Information Commissioner what data they are collecting and the purpose for which it is being collected; Personal data shall be adequate, relevant and not excessive in relation to the purpose or purposes for which they are processed, meaning that Data that is not needed can’t be collected, for example shops collecting a customer’s address when not delivering goods; Personal data shall be accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date, this is can be hard to do, for example, universities find it hard to keep student addresses up to date'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) What does the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations 2003 cover, as regards telecommunication network and service providers only?',
    answer: 'Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulations 2003: protects a citizen’s right to “privacy”. As regards telecommunication network and service providers, it covers: processing of electronic data; location data and billing data; calling or connected line identification; directories of subscribers; security of telecommunications services'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Which UK agency is responsible for data protection?',
    answer: 'Compliance with the Act is regulated and enforced by an independent authority, the Information Commissioner\'s Office, which maintains guidance relating to the Act.'
  }]
},
{
  question: 'Intellectual Property in IT',
  color: 'orange',
  subquestions: [{
    question: 'a) What is Intellectual Property (IP) (provide some examples)? What are the three ways in which IP can be protected in the law?',
    answer: 'Intellectual Property is the name given to legal rights which protect creative works, inventions and commercial goodwill. It protects creative works such as Ideas; Books; Music and Algorithms. The three ways in which intellectual property can be protected by law are Patents which protect inventions, formulae, algorithms, and so on; Trademarks which protect manufacturers and suppliers - product names, logos and so on; and Copyright which covers the right to copy a piece of work. One does not need to apply to be protected by copyright, it comes to existence as the new creative work comes to existence. Although not legally as powerful as patents, copyright lasts for 70 years. Patents are a powerful way to protect intellectual property, one must apply for patent, they are costly and take time to be processed. Patents generally work in a first come first served basis and last for 20 years.'
  },
  {
    question: 'b) In bespoke software development, who owns the IP? What are the exceptions?',
    answer: 'Depends on the contract agreed between supplier and customer, customer usually gets the copyright but there may be proprietary elements for which the developer retains copyright; There may be open-source elements; There may be third party products in the build (copyright owned by the third party); Developer may keep copyright and sell customer a licence to use'
  },
  {
    question: 'c) Can software be patented? What is the difference on software patenting between the USA and Europe?',
    answer: 'In principle, software cannot be patented, although there are software patents, depends on jurisdiction. In the USA, software can be patented if: Software is part of patentable device; Software controls a process that has some physical effect; Software processes data arising from the physical world. In Europe the position is unclear, and there is no uniform practice across countries. European Union draft Directive on the Patentability of Computer-implemented Inventions has been discussed in order to harmonise the interpretation of the national patentability requirements for computer software-related inventions'
  }]
}];
